# Krissy (Dahl) Gianforte

Seattle, WA

Krissy.Gianforte@gmail.com (484) 744 1203

## **Career Summary**

Data scientist and engineer, looking for a role focused on data science. Known for fast learning, self-motivated research, and unrelenting quality.

I have recently completed my Masters in Data Science from UC Berkeley and hope to move fully into a Data Science role after 5 years working as a mechanical engineer. During the UC Berkeley program, I gained practical skills in data manipulation, machine learning, statistical methods, and data visualization. I am excited to continue to creatively solve real-world problems using those new skills.

Building my career in the medical industry instilled solid habits of clear communication and defendable, data-driven decisions. I am known by those I have worked with for diligent documentation, clear rationale, and reliable follow-through. My analyses and reports have withstood FDA scrutiny, and I have defended my work both internally and to the agency. I am excited to apply such signature care and creativity to new and interesting problems.

## **Technical Skills**

Working with structured and unstructured data

Performing statistical analyses (confidence intervals, sample sizing, descriptive statistics, etc)

Developing models for prediction, categorization, language processing, and image analysis using Al/ML Presenting findings to enable data-based decisions

## **Data Science Software and Tools**

Python programming including

Jupyter notebooks

- Machine learning (sklearn)

- Natural language processing (nltk, TensorFlow)

- Visualization (matplotlib)

R (statistical computing language)

Matlab (including image processing and UI)

SQL

Version control (git via command line & github)

Data visualization (html, D3.js, Tableau)

## **Medical Device Regulation & Standards**

ISO 13485 and 21 CFR 820 understanding and experience

Fluency in IEC 60601-1 and associated standards

Familiarity with IEC 14971, MIL-STD 810, RTCA DO-160, ISO 10993

### Education

### California Institute of Technology

B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, 2012

Coursework included engineering design, kinematics and robotics, control theory, learning systems, and programming methods

## **UC Berkeley: School of Information**

Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS), 2019

Coursework included data engineering, statistical methods, experiments and causality, machine learning, natural language processing, data visualization, and data ethics

## Project Highlights: (Demos at KrissyG-hub.github.io)

- Political Language Processing: A project to predict congresspersons' votes regarding the ACA, using their published healthcare statements and NLP models
- Board Game Design: Machine learning analysis of board game patterns using python and sklearn
- Ford GoBike Analysis: SQL exploration of GoBike data resulting in business recommendations
- NBA Player EDA: Tableau visualizations of NBA player statistics, read against existing assumptions
- Propaganda Experiment: Study designed to evaluate propaganda's effects on politics, analyzed in R
- Insurance Ethics: Discussion of the ethical implications of including personal data (ex. wearables data) in insurance calculations

## Krissy (Dahl) Gianforte

Krissy.Gianforte@gmail.com

## **Professional Experience**

## Product Creation Studio (2/2018-6/2018)

Quality Engineer Seattle, WA

• Responsible for all quality engineering project tasks and deliverables at PCS, including requirements development, risk analysis, and verification planning, execution, and reporting

## Philips Healthcare, AED Business (4/2015-12/2017)

Verification Lead, V&V Engineering

Bothell, WA

- Authored hardware verification test plans, sampling plans, protocols, tool packages, and test reports (including compliance testing and certifications)
- Performed statistical analysis on test data to determine test sample sizes and prove product reliability
- Interpreted medical device standards for their application to AED devices and accessories
- Participated in design reviews for input specifications, specifically for testability and consistency
- Developed test tools in C#, including a timing tool for interval testing and an equipment tracking program
- Provided mentorship and guidance to the team as a senior engineer; serves as a process expert to
  ensure that V&V work aligns with the Philips Quality System and applicable standards & regulations
- CAPA owner performed root cause analysis; created action plan including correction, corrective action, and preventive action; documented progress and effectiveness
- Back-room reference for verification matters during audits; front-room experience as subject matter expert

## Weyerhaeuser (7/2013-12/2014)

Mechanical Engineer, Scale and Development Engineering, Timberlands Technology Federal Way, WA

- Programmed control logic and interfaces for multiple PLC automated systems using DirectSoft5
- Developed image analysis program in Matlab (including GUI) for inspection of cellulose fibers products
- Designed and installed custom mechanical equipment for use in lumber mills and development labs

## **Medtronic Diabetes (7/2012-7/2013)**

Associate Mechanical Design Engineer, Research and Development

Northridge, CA

- Wrote design verification test plans and oversaw their execution. Authored corresponding verification reports for product approval and release
- Performed Minitab statistical analyses on test data to quantify design performance
- Constructed Matlab program to standardize a previously subjective visual test method for detecting material stress in injection molded plastic components

#### Research Experience

### Monticello Internship (6/2011-8/2011)

Robotics Institute, Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA Mentor: Dr. David Wettergreen Bucket Wheel Design for a Lightweight Robotic Lunar Excavator

- Designed and constructed prototype digging tools for inclusion on a lunar rover
- Balanced project restrictions (power draw, launch weight) with excavation efficiency
- Executed tests in sandbox and performed analyses using Matlab to determine optimal tool design

## Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship (SURF) (6/2010-8/2010)

Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) Pasadena, CA Mentor: David R. Thompson, PhD Current-Sensitive Path Planning for an Underactuated Free-floating Ocean Sensorweb

- Developed Matlab program to simulate motion of 3000 floating ocean sensors
- Implemented various algorithms to optimize movement of a large-scale system
- First author and presenter of paper at the IROS International Robotics Conference (9/2011)